(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T05:28:27.525434",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
グッドイブニング、マイ教授だぁんチョコ～
Good evening, it's your professor, Choco~
おはライブ！自称悪魔の保健医、癒月ちょこです。
Ohalaive! I'm Choco Yuzuki, the self-proclaimed demonic school nurse.
と いう こと で ね 、 皆 様 、
And so, everyone,
本日は癒月ちょこお誕生日2021お集まり頂きありがとうございます。
thank you so much for gathering here today for Choco Yuzuki's 2021 birthday!
まあ今回はね、このハッシュタグ#癒月ちょこお誕生日2021でいっぱいつぶやきとかね、色々つぶやいてくれたら嬉しいです。
Now, this time, I'd be so happy if you tweeted a lot using the hashtag #ChocoYuzukiBirthday2021 and shared your thoughts!
よかったらね、もうめちゃめちゃ久しぶりに枠では、久しぶりの3Dなんてね、よかったらいっぱいつぶやいてとレンド入りしてくれたらすごく嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
If you'd like, since it's been a really long time having a 3D stream... I'd be so happy if you tweet a lot and get it trending. Please look forward to it!
ああたくさんのおめでとうおめでとうありがとうございます。
Ahh, thank you so much for all the happy birthday messages!
はいということでね、まあ今回お誕生日ということでいろんな企画をね色々と準備して、まあね色々と重大発表とかもあるので、最後まで楽しんでってっていただけたらすごく嬉しいです。
Yes, and so, since it's my birthday today, we've prepared various projects and major announcements, so I'd be so happy if you enjoy it all the way to the end!
そしてね、まあ今日はバレンタインということでね、皆様いかがお過ごしですか？
And you know, since today is Valentine's Day... how is everyone spending it?
まあ、バレンタインっていうイメージよりちょこ先生のお誕生日っていうイメージの方がみんなには強いかな？
Well, rather than Valentine's Day, maybe Choco-sensei's birthday is a stronger image for everyone?
ありがとう。
Thank you!
まあ、今日はね、まちょこのお誕生日ということで、まあせっかくのお誕生日なんだね、ちょこ、お誕生日ケーキ食べたい！
Well, since today is Choco's birthday, and it's a special birthday... I want to eat a birthday cake!
でもその前にね、誕生日だから今日はね、おしゃれなディナーも食べたいなってちょこも思うけど。
But before that, since it's my birthday, Choco was thinking she'd also want to have a nice fancy dinner...
そう。ちょこお腹空い ちゃっ た ん だ よ なっ て 思っ て 。
Right. I was thinking, "Man, Choco is getting hungry."
ん ? なんか いる 。 あんな ところ に おいし そう な ダック が いる !
Hm? Someone's there. There's a delicious-looking duck in a place like that!
いやもうこれは、え結構ペキンダック好きなんだよね。
I mean, I really love Peking duck, you know.
ちょっと、ほら、おい で 。 おい で 、 ほら 。 はよ 、 まさ 。 おい で 、 ほら 。 おい で 、 おい で 、 おい で 、 おい で 。
Hey, come here. Come here. Come on, seriously. Come here, come on. Come here, come here, come here...
せー の ! あ ! ね 、 ちょこ 、 ね 、 ちょっと 待っ て 待っ て 待っ て 待っ て ! ね ?
Ready, go! Ah! Hey, Choco, hey, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait! Hey?
チョコに チョコに食べさせて ねぇ
Feed it to Choco... feed it to Choco, right?
ダメ お前 お前 意外と 意外と早いの
No! Hey, you... you're surprisingly, surprisingly fast!
ちょっ 待って待って
W-wait, wait, wait!
ちょっと待って ちょっと ちょっと待って
Wait a minute! H-hold on, hold on!
あれ？
Huh?
あっ いた 美味そうな 私のご飯 ほら ほら
Ah, there it is! My delicious-looking meal. Look, look!
捕まえた！
Gotcha!
うわあーっ！
Waaah!
なんやねんこいつ
What's with this guy?
なんかうるせえな
So noisy.
喋んな！ライブ逃げで！お前な、一番！
Stop talking! Running away from the stream! Hey, number one!
ちょっと、ちょっと待って！え、スバルなのこれ？ガチ？
Wait, wait, wait! Eh, is this Subaru? For real?
ガチじゃねえよ！その帽子みてスバルって気づいてくれよ！
No it's not! Recognize that I'm Subaru from this hat!
ゴメンゴメンゴメンゴメン！ごめんね！
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry! I'm sorry!
お前のスバル！お前のスバル！
Your Subaru! Your Subaru!
待って待って！そんな暴れないで！そんな暴れないでスバル！スバル暴れないで！
Wait, wait! Don't thrash around like that! Don't thrash around, Subaru! Subaru, stop thrashing!
わかったわかったわかった！離して離して離したら離してくれるから！
I get it, I get it, I get it! Let go, let go, if you let go you'll let me go!
ありがとうね、ありがとう。ありがとう。
Thank you, thank you. Thank you.
うん、可愛いね、スバル。
Yeah, you're cute, Subaru.
ありがとう。なんかちょっと会話すごくない？いろいろちょっとさ。
Thank you. Don't you think there's a huge disparity here? Various things...
え、でも、ちょこせん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Eh, but, Choco-sen, happy birthday!
ありがとう、スバル！
Thank you, Subaru!
お前さ、ツンツンすんじゃねえよ！お前、育ってんだよお前！目に指がよ！
Hey, don't poke me! You're growing, you! My finger went right in your eye!
ごめん、ごめん、ごめん、ごめん！え、ちょっと可愛くてさ、つい触りたくなっちゃうから。
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry! Eh, you're just so cute, I end up wanting to touch you.
でもさ、なかなか過激な座り方をしてるね、それ大丈夫か、それ。え？そのなかなか過激な座り方をしててスバルが気まずいんだけど、ちょっと隠しといてあげるね、ちょうどスバルがね。
But man, that's a pretty hardcore sitting posture. Is that okay? Eh? Subaru is feeling awkward sitting like that, so I'll hide it for you, right where Subaru is.
あ、ね、ありがとうスバル。
Ah, right, thanks Subaru.
ちょっとコメント欄でヤンキーって言われてるけど、ヤンキーじゃねえんだよ！
People in the chat are calling me a delinquent, but I'm not a delinquent!
や、立ったらさ、スバル踏んづけそうで怖いんだよね、結構。
Well, if I stand up, I'm scared I might step on Subaru, honestly.
ちょっと、蹴飛ばさないで！尊い生き物だからスバルは。スバルは意外に火力がね。
Hey, don't kick me! Subaru is a precious creature. Subaru actually has quite a bit of firepower.
ごめんね、スバル。
Sorry, Subaru.
スバルほら、みんなにちゃんと見てもらいな。ほら。見てもらいなじゃねえんだよ！
Subaru, look, make sure everyone sees you properly. Hey. What do you mean 'make sure everyone sees'!?
ちょこ先生の枠の、ちょこメイトの皆さん、お世話になってます。アイドルスバルです。よろしくお願いします！
Everyone in Choco-sensei's stream, Chocomates, thank you for your support. I'm idol Subaru. Nice to meet you!
まあでも、スバル。やあ、すごいね、美味しそうな姿になったね。
Well, but Subaru. Man, it's amazing, you've turned into such a delicious-looking figure.
うーん、まあ、させられたって言ったほうが正確なんだけどね、うん。
Well, 'made to do it' is probably more accurate, yeah.
だからさ、チョコに食べられてみなみい？それは無理ですね。
So, won't you let Choco eat you? That's impossible.
ちょっとそろそろ、当たり前だろお前！当たり前だろお前！わかったスバル、スバルじゃ。
Wait a minute, of course you should! Of course! Okay Subaru, Subaru.
わかった。私と
Got it. With me
私とゲームして私が勝ったら食べられて。
Play a game with me, and if I win, you get eaten.
それはつまり、デスポテスゲームということですか？
Does that mean this is a death-versus game?
イエス！
Yes!
チョコと一緒に、これからジェスチャーゲームをしていただきます！ジェスチャーデスゲームだ！おっしゃ受けて立つぞじゃねえか！
You will now play a gesture game with Choco! A gesture death game! Oh, you accepted it?!
イエス！ルールは簡単。
Yes! The rules are simple.
チョコがこれからジェスチャーをしていくので、スバルはチョコのジェスチャーを当てるだけ。なるほどね？
Choco will now do gestures, and Subaru just has to guess Choco's gestures. Makes sense, right?
そう。で、スバルが先に3問当てることができたら、スバルの勝ち。全部で5問あります。
Right. And if Subaru can guess 3 questions first, Subaru wins. There are 5 questions in total.
なるほどね、まあ、楽勝じゃないですか。そう、スバルが勝ったら、まあ、今回は見逃してあげる。
I see, well, isn't that a piece of cake? Right, if Subaru wins, well, I'll let you off this time.
なるほどね？そうそうそうそう。
I see? That's right, exactly.
うそ、でも、ちょこ先生が負けたら、ぶがわるすぎますよ、こちら側の。
No way, but if Choco-sensei loses, the handicap is way too bad for our side!
や、いやいやいや。あ、チョコが勝、チョコじゃ負けたらスバルを元の姿に戻してあげる。
N-no, no, no. Ah, if Choco loses, I'll return Subaru to her original form.
あ、なるほどね、それは嬉しいね。
Ah, I see, that's great.
そう、その、その可愛いアヒル姿でもチョコはいいんだけどね。
Yeah, though Choco likes you in that cute duck form too.
おい、なめてること言ってんじゃねえぞてめえ、本当に！
Hey, don't say mocking things like that, you bastard, seriously!
分かんないの、スバル。
You don't get it, Subaru.
ほらほら、お前そんなこと言ってるとおまえ胸それ以上なふさっせてやるぞ、本当に！
Look, look, if you keep saying that, I'll make your chest even flatter, seriously!
やめろ！これ以上胸を強めにしないでください！
Stop it! Don't make my chest any flatter!
皆さん、ちょこちゃんのこれ、あの、もう少し薄めのレースにして下さい。お願いします！やめとけマジで！やめとけおま、こんなめでてえ場で！
Everyone, please make Choco's lace a bit thinner. Please! Stop it, seriously! Stop it, man, on such a celebratory occasion!
はい、ということでね、じゃあ、早速やっていきましょうかね。うん。はい。
Alright, with that said, let's get right into it, shall we? Yeah. Right.
じゃあスバル、これからチョコがジェスチャーしていくから、ちゃんと答えてくれるかな？
Then Subaru, Choco is going to do gestures from here on, so can you answer properly?
オッケー！レッツゴー！レッツゴー！チョコ先生もっと真ん中のほうがいいんじゃない？
Okay! Let's go! Let's go! Choco-sensei, wouldn't it be better more in the middle?
なんかスバルど真ん中にいるんだけど。
It feels like Subaru is right in the center.
はい、じゃあね、これからね、それでは早速始めていきたいと思います。
Alright, then, from here on, let's get right started.
じゃあまず第1のお題
Well then, first, the first prompt.
おっ！
Oh!
3、2、1、アート、声！
3, 2, 1, Art, voice!
バスケット！
Basketball!
シュート！
Shoot!
妖怪！？妖怪！？
Youkai?! Youkai?!
沼に沈む…どこどこ落ちてくる妖怪人間って何それ！？
Sinking in a swamp... dropping down like a youkai human, what is that?!
何それ！？
What is that?!
え、よ、なんかえ、これ…
Eh, yo, like, eh, this...
え、あれ？
Eh, huh?
あの、パーツってさ、なに、なに、猫？猫？
Um, parts like, what, what, cat? Cat?
なに、なに、なに、もっと別の動き、別の動き！
What, what, what, do a different movement!
なに、しょこじゃねえか！平泳ぎ！平泳ぎ、平泳ぎ！水泳！
What, isn't that Choco! Breaststroke! Breaststroke, breaststroke! Swimming!
えー？これだったっけ？
Eh? Was it this?
妖怪じゃねえか！猫、猫、猫、猫…
That's a youkai! Cat, cat, cat, cat...
どこに？何に？変える？
Where? What? Changing?
猫じゃねえの？猫じゃ。猫じゃない？猫じゃん。猫じゃない…
Isn't that a cat? It's a cat. Not a cat? It is a cat. Not a cat...
分かってねえな…
You don't get it...
なんだよ！何を打ち上げてんだよ！花火！花火！花火！
What is it! What are you launching! Fireworks! Fireworks! Fireworks!
分かってねえなラスボス！何だおまえ！お前！分かってねえなラスボス！何なんだよ！
You don't get it, final boss! What are you! You! You don't get it, final boss! What is this!
これしかねえだろおまえ！
That's all there is, you!
何それ…？
What is that...?
え、これ…え、トトロ？
Eh, this... eh, Totoro?
ほら、あと5秒しかないよスバル！
Look, you only have 5 seconds left, Subaru!
いやいやいや、待て待て待て！おまえ、一回心の動きにしないでよマジで！これしかないんだよ！
No no no, wait wait wait! Don't make it emotional movements for real! That's all there is!
何なんだよそれ！何それ！
What is that! What is that!
答えは…
The answer is...
え、わかんない、わかんない？みんなも
Eh, I don't get it, you don't get it? Everyone too
わかんねえから今待ってんだよ！
We don't get it, that's why we're waiting right now!
答えは、噴水でーす！
The answer is, a fountain!
え、待って待て、噴水のその上はわかるんだけどさ、そのさ、下のさ、なんか猫っぽい動きは何なの？
Eh, wait wait, I understand the fountain part on top, but what's with that cat-like movement on the bottom?
え、口からあーって出てるやつ。おまえ迷走じゃねえか！迷走じゃねえか！
Eh, the thing coming out of the mouth like 'ah'. You're completely straying! You're straying!
ねえ、ややこしすぎてんだよ！
Hey, it's way too convoluted!
うん、これでわかるべきやったね
Yeah, you should have been able to understand with this.
あな、いやいやいや、わかるねえだろ、そら。ジェスチャーセンス…まあこんな感じか。
Ah, no no no, there's no way you'd get that. Gesture sense... well, something like this.
そうそうそうそう
That's right, that's right.
え、これさ、スバルはコメント見てていいの？
Eh, can Subaru look at the comments?
えっ？えっ？
Eh? Eh?
コメント欄に答えてを求めるんですか？スバルさま
Are you asking the comment section for the answer? Lord Subaru.
おまえ、自分のジェスチャーのクオリティを返してから言えマジで！
Seriously, reflect on your own gesture quality before saying that!
なるほどね、じゃあみんな見ないようにね、します、見ないようにね。あ、ね？見ないようにしますよ。わかった
I see, then everyone don't look, okay, I won't let them look. Ah, right? I won't let them look. Understood.
次なんだっけな。あ、おっけおっけ
What was next. Ah, okay okay.
うん、いこ。じゃあ、次。
Yeah, let's go. Well then, next.
第2問！いいね！
Question 2! Nice!
いきます！どうぞ！3、2、1、アート！
Here we go! Go ahead! 3, 2, 1, Art!
えっ？マリー・アントワネット？マリー・アントワネット？
Eh? Marie Antoinette? Marie Antoinette?
ブリッコ？できません、そんなこと！できません！
Cute act? I can't do that kind of thing! I can't do it!
こわい、こわい！
Scary, scary!
不審者にあったチョコ先生、何これ、なんて…
Choco-sensei encountering a suspicious person, what is this, what...
できません！船長じゃねえかよそれ！
I can't! That's the captain!
え、もっと他に、もっと他に、ちょうだい、動きちょうだい！
Eh, give me more other movements, give me more movements!
なに、何を履いたの今。ミニスカート！ミニスカート！
What, what did you just put on. Miniskirt! Miniskirt!
見えそうでで見えない！
Almost visible yet not visible!
なに？その動き何なの、これ！トイレ、トイレに行きたいけど行けない人！
What? What is that movement, this! Someone who wants to go to the toilet, but can't!
なに？えっ？ストップ！
What? Eh? Stop!
いやいやいや、わかんねえ！えっ、これ私、間違え、あれ？
No no no, I don't get it! Eh, did I make a mistake, huh?
何？ストップ！
What? Stop!
えっ、あれ、あの…ピンクレディー？
Eh, huh, um... Pink Lady?
アントワネットじゃないのこれ？ケツ、フリフリ！
Isn't this Antoinette? Butt shaking!
さあ、スバル、最終的な答えは何でしょう？お答えください。トイレに行きたいマリーン・アントワネット！
Now, Subaru, what is the final answer? Please answer. Marie Antoinette who wants to go to the toilet!
途中まで 途中まで合ってたのに
Even though I had it right up until midway...
え、途中まで合ってるの！？
Wait, you had it right until midway?!
途中まで、え、じゃあトイレに行きたいが合ってんの？
Until midway... Wait, so wanting to go to the bathroom is correct?!
ち、ち、ち、ち、トイレに行きたいじゃない！
N-N-N-No, it's not wanting to go to the bathroom!
何に？
Then what?
正解は言ってんだよ！
I was saying the correct answer!
え！？
What?!
正解は、うん。ぶりっこな、ナルシストのぶりっ子でした！
The correct answer was... um, a narcissistic girlish act!
おーい！こんなの分かるかよ！お前！
Hey! Who could guess that, you?!
ちょっとこれ、残りの３つ、あの、正解しないと、子ども泣いちゃうわ。
If I don't get the remaining three right, kids are gonna cry.
これふんわりす、いい塩梅ですよ、これ！これちょっと今コメント見ましたけど、いい塩梅ですよ、これ！
This is a nice, just-right vibe! I just checked the comments, it's just right!
分かるわけねえだろ！ぶりっ子じゃねえよ！
There's no way to know that! That wasn't girlish!
お前、そんなデスゲームでいいのかよ！お前はデスゲーマーの風上にも置けねえやつだ！
Are you okay with such a death game?! You're a total disgrace to death gamers!
わかったわかった。でも残り３問は、あ、じゃあ分かりやすくしてあげるよ、しょうがないな。
Alright, alright. But for the remaining three... fine, I'll make it easier for you.
ええ！やったあ！やったね、やったね！
Yay! Yes! Nice, nice!
それでは、３問目！さんさん、にに、
Now then, question 3! Three three, two two,
ちちち、あくと、あくと！
One one one, act, act!
いや、私３問目どっちでしたかなど思って。確かこっち…しっかりして、ちょこ先！ちょこ先が、
Wait, I was wondering which one question 3 was. I'm sure it's—Get it together, Choco-sensei!
えっさ、ほっさ、えっさ、うおー！おー！背骨、背骨！背骨がぐいぐいぐいぐい、何々それ！？
Hessa, hossa, whoa! Whoa! Your spine! Your spine is twisting all over, what is that?!
ジェットコースター！ジェットコースター！えっ、待て、これが…待て、
Jet coaster! Jet coaster! Wait, is this... wait,
正解！
Correct!
正解はジェットコースターでしたー！
The correct answer was a roller coaster!
マジでね、登山家とで迷った。登山、登山してるおばあちゃんと迷ったんだよ、お前！最初完全にリュック背負ってただろ！
Seriously, I hesitated between a mountaineer and... I hesitated between an old lady mountain climbing, you! You were totally wearing a backpack at first!
おむすびころりんの動きだっただろそれ！おむすびころりんの動きだっただろマジで！お前、かなりおむすび落としてんじゃねえよ！落としたのスパルじゃねえわ！お前ではどっちかっていうと…
That was straight out of 'The Rolling Rice Ball'! You dropped way too many rice balls! Wait, I didn't drop them! If anything, you...
はい、続いて。続いて第４問目！はい、さんさん、にに、いちいち、あくと！
Okay, next. Next is question 4! Three three, two two, one one, act!
ピヨピヨピヨ、鶏、アヒル、スバル、鶏、白鳥、ピヨピヨピヨピヨ…おっと何かが有る？
Piyo piyo piyo, chicken, duck, Subaru, chicken, swan, piyo piyo... Oh, is there something?
足が！足が！足がやられた！もう僕のことは置いといて欲しい！ピヨ、ピヨピヨ、ピヨピヨピヨピヨ…ピヨーー！
My leg! My leg! My leg is hurt! Just leave me behind! Piyo, piyo piyo...
何これ！？何なの？ちょっと、何も、飛べない、飛べない、飛べない鳥はただの鳥…飛べない鳥は…あ、あ、アヒル、アヒル、鶏、
What is this?! What is—Wait, nothing... A flightless bird is just a bird... A flightless bird is—Ah, duck, duck, chicken,
ピヨ、ピヨピヨピヨピヨ、あ、ペンギン、ペンギン！
Piyo, piyo piyo, oh, penguin, penguin!
駄チョウ、駄チョウ、駄チョウじゃない！えっ、何？ピヨピヨピヨピヨ…
Ostrich, ostrich, not an ostrich! Eh, what? Piyo piyo piyo...
更新？ちょっとびっくりした。もう、スバル、ちょっと、何なのそれ？
Renewal? That startled me. Subaru, wait, what is that?
誰か…ヒント、ヒント、ヒント、ヒント！ほら、答え言ってね？わざわざ…ひよこ、ひよこ、鶏、
Someone... hint, hint, hint, hint! Look, say the answer! Even though... chick, chick, chicken,
どうど、歩いているひよこ、歩いている鶏、アヒル、歩く…わかんないよ！
Walking chick, walking chicken, duck, walking... I have no idea!
ちこさん、答えをどうぞー！アヒル！
Chiko-san, please give us the answer! Duck!
正解でございまーす！アヒル！
That is correct! Duck!
私も正解してんのに何で私ぶりっ子されちゃったと思ってたよ！ジャッチ前ぞこれ！ジャッチ！ジャッチお前後で名前書いとけよマジで！やっぱりスバルじゃねえか！じゃあ最後の問題にまいりましょうか！
Even though I got it right, why did you think I was acting girlish?! Judge this! Judge, write your name down later, seriously! It was Subaru after all! Let's move on to the final question!
はい。それでは、最後の問題でございます。はい。この最後の問題まで、
Yes. Now then, for the final question. Yes. Up until this final question...
ううん
Yeah...
にに
Two, two...
いちいち
One, one...
あくあー！？
Aqua?!
違います！
Wrong!
頑張れちょこせん！
You can do it, Choco-sen!
マリン船長！
Captain Marine!
おっ？
Oh?
ちょこせん、お、終わったよ？
Choco-sen, it's over, you know?
ちょっとまだやり足りない？
Do you still want to keep going?
もしかしてマリン船長までやり足りない？
Could it be you want to keep going as Captain Marine?
まだやり足りない？
Still want more?
ほら、しょ、マリンでーす！
There, I'm... Marine!
いやーーっ！
Nooo!
で、バカ怒られるからやめようマジで、バカ怒られるから本当に。
I'll get chewed out big time, seriously, I'll really get chewed out.
はい、ってことで答えはマリン船長でしたー！イェーイ！
Anyway, the answer was Captain Marine! Yay!
あれ？ちょこせんこれ？
Huh? Choco-sen, what about this?
ということでね、スバル…
So, Subaru...
ジェスチャーゲーム…死にそうや、お前。
Charades... You look like you're gonna die.
ということで、スバル様、ちょっとこっち来て。
So, Lady Subaru, come over here for a second.
あ、やり直し…元に戻してくれるの？
Oh, you're redoing it... Changing me back?
スバル、おいで、こっち…
Subaru, come here...
元に、ちゃんとスバルにばっちりしか、誇りできないからちょっとね、まだこの体に慣れてないんだよ。
I need to turn you back properly so you can show off, since I'm still not used to this body.
よいしょ、よいしょ。スバルの姿、元の姿に戻してくれ、ちょこせん。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Put Subaru back to her original form, Choco-sen.
わかった、わかった。
Got it, got it.
ありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you, thank you.
スバルおいで。
Subaru, come here.
ありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you, thank you.
ありがとう、ありがとう。やっぱりちょこせん優しいんだなあ。
Thank you, thank you. Choco-sen is so kind after all.
さてと、ま、これでね、食料調達もできたことだし、早速料理していきましょうかね。
Well then, now that we've procured our food, let's start cooking right away.
え？ほら、スバル、おいで。
Huh? Hey, Subaru, come here.
じゃあ、皆さん、スバル、じゃあ、またね！ありがとうございました！お邪魔しました！
Well everyone, Subaru, see you later! Thank you very much! Thanks for having us!
みんな、また後でね！すり抜けるように、ばいばーい！
Everyone, see you later! Slipping right through, bye-bye!
はーい！
Yay!
よーし、おし、スバルかわいいね！
Alright, alright, Subaru is so cute!
じゃあ、何で行くの？何で行くの？
So where are we going? Where are we going today?
今日は魔界の遊園地行くのよ、スバル。
Today we're going to the Demon Realm amusement park, Subaru.
遊園地なの？
An amusement park?
そう、いいね！
That's right, awesome!
いや、魔界の遊園地といえばね、なんと目玉は…
You know, speaking of the Demon Realm amusement park...
おばけやしき！
The haunted house!
いえーい、いねいね、おばけやしき！いねいね！
Yay, nice nice, a haunted house! Nice nice!
スバルもおばけになってみたい？
Do you want to become a ghost too, Subaru?
お化けになってこと、いいね！うん。
Becoming a ghost, that sounds nice! Yeah.
お化けになってもらいたいか、スバルは。
So you want to become a ghost, Subaru?
お化けやっほーやってみたい！
I wanna try being a ghost!
じゃあ、チョコがその願い叶えてあげましょう！
Then Choco will grant that wish for you!
ちょっと待って、危ない危ない。それは危ない。そのテンションで言うことじゃない、それはちょこせん。
Wait, dangerous, dangerous. That's not something you say with that tone, Choco-sen.
おちて、ちょこせんマジで。
Calm down, Choco-sen, seriously.
いや、だってさ、お化けになりたいんでしょ？いや、チョコが叶えたげるわよ。
Well, I mean, you wanted to become a ghost, right? Choco will make it happen.
おしまい！せーのっ！
That's it! Ready, set!
あ、危ない危ない危ない、それ、それやっちゃう、お前！
Ah, dangerous! You're gonna do that!
やっちゃう！やっちゃう！やっつけちゃう！
I'll do it! I'll do it! I'll finish you off!
やめろ！やめろ！
Stop it! Stop it!
嘘ね、うん。
Just kidding, yeah.
なんか、スバル、危ない危ない来てた。
It looked like things were getting dangerous for Subaru.
羽根が1枚似てたぐらいだわ。
You only looked like you had one wing.
1枚どころじゃねえよ！お前！
That's more than one wing! You!
命拾いしたな、お前。そのプリケツこっちに向けなスバル、やってやるよ。
You're lucky you escaped with your life. Turn that cute butt this way, Subaru.
いや、無理無理無理、せーのっ、やめて、やめて、やめて！
No, way, way, ready, set, stop, stop, stop!
危えな！
That was close!
もう、これ使えないわね、もう。使えないじゃねえんだよ、おめえ、そんなことしてるから胸が直されるんだよ、おめえ。
Man, we can't use this anymore. That's why your chest gets fixed, you!
え、じゃあこれ取ったらいい？
Uh, so should I take this off?
いや、それはやめてください、危ないから、マジで。いろんな意味で危ないから。
No, please don't do that, because it's dangerous, seriously.
わかった、じゃあ、ほら、スバル何も持ってないからこっちおいで。
Understood. Well then, look, Subaru has nothing, so come over here.
本当に？
Really?
うん、ほら、ないよ。
Yeah, look, nothing here.
しょうがないな、もう誕生日だしね。
I suppose it can't be helped, it's your birthday after all.
信じてあげるよ、二人のキズナ！
I'll trust you, our bond!
かわいいね、スバル。
You're so cute, Subaru.
まあ、二人のキズナだからね、あ、ちょこせんせー。
Well, since it's our bond, oh, Choco-sensei.
なに？ほら、こっちおいで。
What? Come over here, look.
いいよ。そうだよ、ちょこせんね、ちょっと優しくして。せーの、なんか…
Okay. That's right, Choco-sen, be a little nice. Ready, like...
待て待て、ちょこ、ねえ、あの、今日は北京ダック食べ るって決めてたの。
Wait, Choco, we decided to eat Peking duck today.
いやいやいや、待って待って！
No, no, no, wait, wait!
まあまあ、スバル。
Now, now, Subaru.
いやいや！
No way!
ちがう、ちがう、ちがう、あ、危なかった。
No, no, no, ah, that was close.
当たりめえだ！
Of course it was!
いや、そうじゃねえんだ。
No, that's not what I meant.
お前サイコパスか？マジで。
Are you a psychopath, seriously?
まあまあまあまあ、スバル。
Now, now, now, now, Subaru.
よーし、おめでとう！
Alright, congratulations!
お誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう、スバル！
Happy birthday! Thank you, Subaru!
あれ？スバル？
Huh? Subaru?
スバル？
Subaru?
もしかして…ねえ、ちょっと、こう言うときは知ってるわよ、チョコ。人工呼吸をすれば生き返るって！
Could it be... Choco knows what to do in times like this. Give artificial respiration!
じゃあ、早速…
Well then, right away...
いやいやいや、やめてやめてやめて、ちょっと待って待って待って、ちょこせん。
No, stop, stop, stop, wait, wait, wait, Choco-sen.
まずいその深呼吸とか大丈夫です。
Wait, that deep breath and stuff is fine!
何？って。
What, you ask?
スバル 大丈夫っそ？うん。
Subaru, are you okay? Yeah.
いやいや無理無理無理ちょっと気合入れるために食べただけだから。
No, no way! I just ate it to pump myself up!
いや気合入れるためににごっくんしたほう…
No, to get pumped up, you swallowed it whole...
ほらうるさいわよ口が。
Hey, your mouth is too loud!
ほらねーうーーん！
See? Ugh—!
はーい、ということでね、皆様スバジャクはいかがだったでしょうか？
Hiii, so anyway everyone, how was Subaru-Choco?
まあね、まあスバルちょっとあぶったぐらいだから大丈夫なんですけど、
Well, you know, Subaru was just slightly toasted, so she's fine,
そうペチンクはね
but Pechinku...
やっぱローストしなきゃいけないから、
She has to be roasted,
まあこの後どうなったのかは皆様のご想像にお任せいたします。
so I'll leave what happened next to your imagination.
ということでね、まあおいしくいただいたところで
And so, after having a delicious meal...
なんかね運営さんがちょこのためにケーキをご用意していただいたみたいで、
Apparently, management prepared a cake specially for Choco,
ちょっとデザートにケーキを食べようかなって思います。
so I think I'll have some cake for dessert.
いでよ、ケーキ！
Appear, cake!
なー！？
Whoa—?!
わーてちょ、ちょっちょっわちょっと、ちょ、ちょ、ちょっと
Wa— wait, w-w-wait, w-wait, wait!
いやめっっちゃでかい！
Man, it's super huge!
おーおっきい！おいしそう！
Ooh, it's big! It looks delicious!
じゃあね、それではちょこのお誕生日いただきまーす！
Well then, Choco's birthday, let's dig in!
おいしょっと。ちょっと待ったー！
Heave-ho. Wait just a minute!
だめだよ、ちょこ先生。
That's no good, Choco-sensei.
め、メルさま？
M-Mel-sama?
深夜の天才ヴァンパイア、夜空メルだよー！
The midnight genius vampire, Yozora Mel!
な、何がだめなんですか、メルさま？
W-What's no good about it, Mel-sama?
ちょこ先生、えーお誕生日まずはおめでとうございます！あー、メルさま、ありがとうー！
Choco-sensei, um— first of all, happy birthday! —Aah, Mel-sama, thank you—!
でもケーキを食べるのはメルと勝負に勝ってからにしてね。
But eating the cake— make it after you win a contest against Mel, okay?
ガッチ！？ガッチ！？ガッチ！？
Seriously?! Seriously?! Seriously?!
目の前にあるのに。うん、我慢、我慢。うん。もうメルさまの頼みならしょうがないな。
Even though it's right in front of me. Yeah, bear with it, bear with it. Well, if it's Mel-sama's request, it can't be helped.
メルから、下ろしておこう。うん、勝負をね、持ちかけたいと思うんだけど。うん。いいかな？
Let me put it down first. Yeah, I want to propose a contest. Yeah. Is that okay?
もちろん！まあメルさまの勝負ならね、楽勝で勝っちゃうと思うけどね。じゃあ勝負のルール説明をするね。うん。
Of course! Well, if it's Mel-sama's contest, I think I'll win easily. Now, let me explain the rules of the contest. Yeah.
今から3つのシチュエーションを用意します。そのシチュエーションに合ったセリフをメルが言うので、そのセリフに合わせてちょこ先生は身振り手振り動いてください。
Starting now, I will prepare three situations. Mel will say lines fitting those situations, so Choco-sensei, please move and gesture along with those lines.
もう任せてほしいわ、それは。3つやってみて、見ているみんなをドキドキさせることができたら、ちょこ先生の勝ち。
"Leave it to me, you want?" Well, that's... If you try all three and make the viewers' hearts skip a beat, Choco-sensei wins.
ドキドキさせる。なるほどね。ドキドキさせることができたらケーキ食べていいよ。
Make them skip a beat. I see. If you can make them skip a beat, you can eat the cake.
ガッチえ、頑張るー！だから頑張ってね。
Seriously? Eh, I'll do my best—! So do your best, okay?
待たせてほしい。メルの無茶ぶりにちゃんと対応できるかなー。
Keep me waiting, I want. Wonder if I can properly handle Mel's unreasonable demands.
いやあもうメルキスの絆見せてあげましょうよ、メルさま。そう、だね。よし。
Oh man, let's show them the bond of Mel-Choco, Mel-sama. Right, right. Alright.
じゃあ早速ひとつ目のシチュエーション行ってみよっか。はーーい。
Shall we try the first situation? Hii—i.
シチュエーション、ワオーン！
Situation: Whoa—on!
あ、肩、肩、シチュエーション1はバレンタインに告白をするシチュエーションです。
Ah, shoulder, shoulder. Situation 1 is a confession on Valentine's Day.
いや、これはドキドキやね。ね、ドキドキだね。
Man, this is heart-pounding. Hey, it's heart-pounding, right?
なるほどね。メルさまが告白セリフを言うからちょこは、メルさまが言ってるようにちょこが言ってるように動けばいいってことね。そう。いや、任せてよ。
I see. Mel-sama will say the confession lines, so Choco just needs to move as if Choco is saying them, right? Right. Well, leave it to me.
大丈夫？いやメルキスのね、意地合わせしてあげますよ、もうちょこが。任せてほしい。
Are you okay? Well, I'll match Mel-kiss's determination, Choco will! I want you to leave it to me.
わかった。じゃあ、早速ちょこ先生の告白をするバレンタインシチュエーション、いきます！
Understood. Well then, let's go straight to Choco-sensei's Valentine confession situation!
あの、急に呼び出してごめんね。
Um, sorry for calling you out so suddenly.
バレンタインでしょ？
Valentine's, right?
だからさぁ、その…
So, um...
チョコを作ってきたの。
I made you some chocolate.
ちょっと、ちょっと！
Hey, wait a minute!
誰がチョコだけにチョコレートよ！
Who gives chocolate to "Choco" just like that!
ラジヲじゃないんだから！
This isn't a radio show!
もう、馬鹿…！
Geez, dummy...!
一応言っておくけど、
I'll say this just in case,
これ、義理じゃないんだからね！
This isn't obligation chocolate, you know!
本命よ？
It's my true feelings, okay?
チョコの気持ち、受け取ってくれる？
Will you accept Choco's feelings?
あなたのことが好きです。
I'm in love with you.
付き合ってください。
Please go out with me.
いや、て、照れる方がちょっとドキドキしちゃった！
Man, getting embarrassed made my heart race so much!
バレンタインに告白をする シチュエーション
[Situation: Confessing on Valentine's Day]
いや、メルはね、あくまでチョコ先生の気持ちをね、今代弁してるだけなのだ…
I mean, Mel is just speaking on behalf of Choco-sensei's feelings right now...
なるほどね。
I see.
メル様の破壊力がすごいのよ！
Mel-sama's destructive power is incredible!
ほんと！ 恥ずかしいよ、メルも！
Seriously! It's so embarrassing for Mel too!
どうかな、みんなドキドキしてますか？
I wonder, is everyone's heart racing?
で、メルじゃなくてチョコ先生からのチョコレートなのだからね？チョコレート、みんなもらいました？ちゃんと。
So, remember, this is chocolate from Choco-sensei, not Mel, okay? Did everyone get their chocolate properly?
もらえたかな？
Did you get it?
じゃあ、続いてシチュエーションツー！ツー、ツーもドキドキさせることができるかねえ？
Now, onto Situation 2! Can you make hearts race for Situation 2 as well?
いや、できるかなあ？どうせならね、言ってる風にしたいから、ちょっとチョコのマイクはオフでお願いしますね！
I wonder if I can? Since I want it to sound authentic, I'd like Choco's mic turned off, please!
やってる最近はよろしくお願いします！じゃあ、メル様お願いします！
Recently we've been doing this, so please look forward to it! Now, Mel-sama, please!
バレンタインに告白をされる シチュエーション
[Situation: Being confessed to on Valentine's Day]
はい！シチュエーションツーは、チョコ先生がなんと告白をされるシチュエーションになります！
Yes! Situation 2 is a situation where Choco-sensei gets confessed to!
屋上じゃーん。
It's on the rooftop.
いや、これはドキドキするね！チョコ屋上で告白されんの！？
Man, this makes my heart race! Choco getting confessed to on the rooftop!?
じゃあ、行きますよ！
Well then, here we go!
どうしたの？どうしたの？
What's wrong? What's wrong?
ええ、もう今日のお仕事は終わってるわよ。
Um, today's work is already finished, you know.
ちょ、チョコ先生のマイクが入ってるみたい。
W-Wait, it looks like Choco-sensei's mic is on.
ああ、なるほどね。あの、配信には載せないでほしいです。お願いします。
Ah, I see. Um, please don't broadcast that on the stream. I'm begging you.
めったぞ。
Gotcha.
じゃあ、はい、もう一回行きます！カン！
Well then, yes, let's go again! Clang!
あら、どうしたの？こんなところに呼び出して、何か相談ごとかしら？
Oh, what's wrong? Calling me out to a place like this, is it some kind of consultation?
ええ、もう今日のお仕事は終わってるわよ。
Yes, today's work is already done, you know.
なんだか様子が変ね。顔もなんだか終始熱でもあるの？
Somehow your demeanor is strange. Is your face also running a fever the whole time?
保健室のベッド空いてるから、少し休む？
The infirmary bed is open, so should you rest a bit?
え？これチョコレート？チョコにくれるの？嬉しい。でもどうして？
Eh? Is this chocolate? You're giving it to me? I'm so happy. But why?
まあ、嬉しいわ。バレンタインデーだものね。
Well, I'm happy. It's Valentine's Day, after all.
ねえ、これってどういう意味かしら？本命チョコって受け取ってもいいのかな？
Hey, what does this mean? Can I accept this as genuine chocolate?
本命？チョコも…続きは…
Genuine? Choco too... The rest is...
ホワイトデーで期待していてね。
I'm counting on you
カン、ゴー！ゴー！ゴー！
Go! Go! Go!
どうだった？
How was that?
バレンタインに告白をされるシチュエーション。
Confessing on Valentine's Day.
なかなかギャップきょじゃん。
That's pretty unexpected, right?
いや、ちょっとガチ恋距離やばかったね。
No, that distance was seriously dangerous.
今。
Right now?
ねえ、ちょっと。ときめいちゃうよ。
Right? My heart skipped a beat!
もう、メル様の声であざったら、とっくにちっちゃうよ、もう！
If I heard Mel-san's voice, my heart would stop!
じゃあちょっと、メルもね、チョコ先生の動きを見て、
Well, Mel was also watching Choco-sensei's movements,
ドキドキしてたけど、ガチ？
so she was all excited, right?
みんなはもっとドキドキしてるんじゃないかな？
Everyone's probably even more excited, huh?
これはどうかな？
What do you think about this?
次で最後？
Is the next one the last?
そうだね、次で最後になります。
That's right, next will be the last one.
もっとメルともっと一緒にいたいんだけどな、チョコ。
I actually wanted to spend more time with Mel-san, though...
でも今日は特別な日だから、わかった。
But today's a special day, so okay.
終わったら2人でいようね。
When we're done, let's do it together, okay?
わかった、頑張る。
Okay, I'll do my best.
じゃあ次のシチュエーション、シチュエーション3、ラスト！
All right, next is situation three...
ラスト！
Last!
バレンタインに告白を見守るシチュエーションです。
Watching over a confession on Valentine's Day.
見守る？
Watching over...
Watching over?
覗いてるの？
What do you mean?
ガチ？
Seriously?
見守るでもね、いろんなシチュエーションがあるからね。
Watching over has various situations, too, you know.
あ、あ、こういう感じなんだね。
Ah, so this is what it's like.
オッケー、オッケー、わかった。
Okay, okay, I see.
準備はいいですか？
Preparation is good?
任せてほしい。
Leave it to me.
よし。
All right.
じゃあ、告白を見守るチョコ先生まで、3、2、1。
Up until Choco-sensei, who watches over the confession, in 3, 2, 1...
カン。
Go!
あらあら、まあまあ。
Oh, my, well, well, well.
あそこにいるのは金髪のエルフ？
Is that person over there a blonde elf?
と金髪の騎士？
Or a blonde knight?
女子生徒が2人いるわね。
Or maybe two female students?
何してるのかしら。
What are they doing, I wonder?
もう少し近づいてみましょう。
Let's get a little closer and see.
あれはチョコレートかしら。
Is that chocolate, I wonder?
そっか、今日はバレンタインデーだものね。
Ah, that's right, today is Valentine's Day, after all!
待って、あれは。
Wait, that's...
トモチョコなら恐れても
Even if it's Tomochoco,
本命チョコ、立つなの？
is it Honmeichoco?
ちょっと待って。
Wait, wait,
会話が聞き取れないじゃない。
I can't hear what they're saying!
もっと、もっと近づかなきゃ。
I have to get closer!
バレないように、そーっと、そーっと。
So that they don't find out... Shh, shh, shh.
バレ、バレてないよね。
Ah, they didn't notice, right?
でももうもどかしいわね！
But, man, I'm getting impatient!
早くチョコレートを渡しなさいよ！
Hurry up and hand over the chocolate!
もう、そこの2人！
Hey, those two!
どう考えても両思いなんだから、さっさとお互いのチョコレートを交換しなさい！
No matter how you think about it, it's mutual feelings, so hurry up and exchange chocolates!
やべ、バレちゃった。
Ah, crap, I got caught.
ということで、皆様いかがだったでしょうか？
So, everyone, how was it?
いや、めちゃくちゃ面白いな、この企画。
Man, this project is hilarious!
なんか、チョコ先生らしかったね、ちょっと。
It felt very Choco-sensei-like, didn't it?
ガチ？
Really?
いや、でもわかる。チョコもよくサプライズしようと思ってやるんだけど、結構バレること。
Yeah, but I get it, Choco also tries to surprise people and does it, but she ends up getting caught.
そうなの？
Is that so?
うわ、聞こえない、聞こえないと思って、なんか準備してるじゃん。準備し終わって、いつ出ていこうかなって、あの、タイミングを見計らうのよ。
Thinking, "I hope they won't notice, I hope they won't notice," she prepares, and once she's done preparing, she thinks about when to go out, and tries to time it.
で、
Right?
あ、タイミングを見計らおうと思ってドアを開けようとした瞬間に、その、サプライズ相手がドア開けて、あ、みたいな。あ、バレちゃった、みたいな。
Trying to time it and trying to open the door, just at that moment, the surprise target opens the door... like that.
こと多いよ、けっこう。
That happens a lot, quite a bit.
でも、バレても嬉しいもんね。
Being found out is happy, too, right?
そう、嬉しい。でも、でもね、メル様とね、出っくわすことメ
Yeah, it's happy, but... but you know, Mel-san, being together with you...
うん、メルも誘ってくれてありがとう！
Yeah, thank you for inviting me too, Mel!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
それじゃあね、みんなドキドキコメント見る限りね、みんなドキドキ
So, judging by everyone's nervous chat comments...
してたようなので、ご褒美としてチョコ先生ケーキ食べていいよ！
it looks like everyone's been so nervous, so as a reward, Choco-sensei can eat cake!
やったー！
Yay!
ああじゃあ、いっぱい一杯召し上がれ。
Ah, well then, eat up to your heart's content.
食べちゃうよ？食べちゃうよ？
I'm gonna eat it? I'm gonna eat it?
食べて！いでよフォーク！フォーク！
Eat it! Come forth, fork! Fork!
ていっ！ていっ！おっ、来た来た来た。いただきまーす！わあ、美味しそう。
Hah! Hah! Oh, it's here! Itadakimasu! Wow, it looks delicious.
あーーん、あー、うんうん、うんうんうんうん、あーん... ねぇ、美味しい！美味しいよメル様！
Aah... Aah, yum, yum, yum... Aah... Hey, it's delicious! It's delicious, Mel-sama!
よかった、ふふ。
I'm glad, hehe.
まあね、ん、でもね、実はね、ちょっと、チョコとメル様ね、みんなにこのケーキだけじゃなくて、ちょっとバレンタインのプレゼントがあるんですよ。
Well... but you know, actually, Choco and Mel-sama have a Valentine's present for everyone besides just this cake!
あ、そうなんだ。実はね！一日チョコとメル様...
Ah, is that so? Actually! Choco and Mel-sama...
と いうことで、で、チョコとメル様からのバレンタインプレゼントは、こちらだー！
And so, Choco and Mel-sama's Valentine's present is... right here!
こちらだー！じゃんじゃーん！
Right here! Ta-da!
このあとね、この3D放送が終わった22時から、なんと、初めての、初めての、初めての、メルキース歌ってみた！今回...
After this 3D broadcast ends at 22:00, we're releasing our very first MelKiss cover song!
ずっとね、やりたいやりたいって言ってたんだけど、なかなかね、ちょっと忙しくてできなくてね。でも今回は、そう！メル様「スイートマジック」歌いたいよって言ったらね、いいよって言ってくれて。ねえ、一緒に歌おうねって言って今回実現いたしましたー！ねえ！えへー！
We've been wanting to do it for so long, but we were so busy we couldn't. But this time, when I said, "Mel-sama, I want to sing 'Sweet Magic'!", she said sure! So we made it happen this time! Right? Hehe!
いやー、とってもね、イラストもね、動画もね、可愛い感じに仕上がってるので、ぜひぜひこのあと22時からよろしくお願いします、皆様ぜひぜひ聴いてみてください。
The illustration and video turned out so cute, so please check it out starting at 22:00. Everyone, please give it a listen!
絶対見てね！見てね！見てね！それと、あと、もうひとつ！
Definitely watch it! Watch it! Watch it! And also, one more thing!
てれん、たらーん！ま、これはチョコのチャンネルじゃなくて、メル様のチャンネルなのですが、もう、ちょうどね、21時、もう公開されているのですが、地味チョコ、なんとこの3Dで、歌っちゃいましたー！やったー！
Ta-da! Now, this isn't on Choco's channel, but on Mel-sama's, but it's already premiered at 21:00—we actually sang "Gimme Chocolate!!" in 3D! Yay!
ミルクチョコ先生はね、あの、なんだろう、サイドにね、いて、わちゃわちゃしてますけど、ぜひぜひ、めっちゃめちゃかっこいいんだよ、この曲。かっこいいし可愛いしね！そう、いやもうチョコね、もう、これはね、出た瞬間ね、あの、送って貰ったの。もう、あー！ってなった。可愛い最高！そう、ぜひぜひ皆様、ただいま公開されているのでこちらのほうもチェックしてみてください！
Milk Choco-sensei is on the side being all lively, but it's super cool, this song. It's cool and cute! So, Choco received it the moment it came out and went, "Ahhh!" It's so cute and amazing! So everyone, please check it out as it's out right now!
と いうことでね、皆様、ぜひぜひメルキスよろしくお願いします！お願いしまーす！えー、チョコ先生、改めてお誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう、メルちゃん！生まれてきてくれて本当ありがとう！嬉しい、ありがとう！
And so everyone, please support MelKiss! Thank you! Choco-sensei, happy birthday once again! Thank you, Mel-chan! Thank you so much for being born! I'm so happy, thank you!
そろそろメルはね、おじゃましょ、おじゃ、ん？違う、退散、退散しようと思います。行っちゃうの？うーん、でも残りの時間もみんなと楽しく過ごしてね。
I think I'm about to take my leave. Are you going? Urm, but spend the rest of the time having fun with everyone.
わかった！ありがとうメル様、またねー！ありがとう、またねー、またねー！
Understood! Thank you Mel-sama, see you later! Thank you, see you, see you!
ということでね、皆様、ぜひぜひ歌ってみたの方も聴いてみてください、ということで、まあね、ケーキも食べて、いろいろ食べたことだし、まあね、最後はチョコこう見えてアイドルなんで、アイドルらしくライブ会場に向かいたいと思います。ライブ会場への道は、ぜひチョコメート様たちで彩っていただけたら嬉しいです！
And so everyone, please make sure to listen to the cover song as well! So, since we've eaten cake and everything, well, at the end, Choco is an idol after all, so I'd like to head to the live venue like an idol. I'd be happy if you all, Chocomates, could grace the path to the live venue!
なんと今回ね
This time, you see...
スパチャレッドカーペットと 普通のスーパーチャットでは
on the Super Chat red carpet and regular Super Chats,
今回チョコ、プレゼント募集してなくておてがみだっ ていうお誕生日のやつを取らせていただいてたんですけど
this time, Choco wasn't accepting gifts, just letters for my birthday, which I had allowed people to send.
是非ここで、そう、めちゃね、あったのリップに 「チョコ先生、なんでおてがみだけなの？」みたいな
But I wanted to give you a chance here—many people reacted on Twitter like, "Choco-sensei, why just letters?"
あれ？「プレゼント送りたかったのに！」みたいな
"Wait, I wanted to send a gift!"
まあ是非是非、皆様プレゼントもね いただけたら、
So please, if you'd like to send gifts as well,
ここでいただけたらチョコは嬉しいです と言うことで！
if you can give them here, Choco would be so happy! So with that...
それでは！ レッツ！ スタート！
Now then, let's start!
お誕生日、おめでとうー！
Happy birthday to me!
そうなんです。今回はねみんなにとっておいてって言ったのはこのためです。
That's right. The reason I told everyone to save them for this time is for this very moment.
ありがとう、いつも。
Thank you, as always.
そう、久しぶりの3D配信、皆様はいかがでしょうかー？
That's right, how do you all like this long-awaited 3D stream?
運営さんアップでお願いします！
Management-san, close-up please!
運営さんありがとうございます！ ありがとうございます！
Management-san, thank you so much! Thank you!
ちょっとチョコの画面アップでいいですか？
Can we get a close-up on Choco's screen?
みんな、いつも、ありがとうー！
Everyone, thank you as always!
そう、最近ね、ちょっといろいろバタバタしとって
Yeah, lately I've been super busy with various things,
配信頻度が減っちゃってますが、
so my streaming frequency has dropped, but...
これからもね、癒月ちょこ頑張っていこうと思うので、これからもよろしくお願いします！
I'm going to keep doing my best as Yuzuki Choco, so I hope you'll continue to support me!
ありがとう！みんな、お誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！ありがとうみんな！
Thank you! Everyone, happy birthday to me! Thank you! Thank you everyone!
それでは、ライブ会場の方にいきたいと思います。
Now then, I'd like to head over to the live venue.
今日はみんな来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for coming today!
デビューして、みんなのおかげで今回3回目の「お誕生日」を迎えることができました！
Thanks to everyone since my debut, I'm able to celebrate my 3rd birthday!
いつもみんな応援ありがとう！
Thank you all for always supporting me!
今日はバレンタインデーということで、
Today is Valentine's Day,
まあみんなから、今すごいお祝いをいただいたので、
and since I've received such wonderful celebrations from everyone,
チョコからも…チョコは実際にはあげれないんですけど、
Choco wants to give something back too... well, I can't give real ones, but
愛のこもったおとなプレゼントをしたいと思います！
I want to give you all a mature, love-filled present!
よかったら最後まで聞いてってくれたら嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you listen all the way to the end!
最後にね、よかったら重大告知もあるので、
And lastly, if you're interested, there's a major announcement,
ぜひぜひ楽しみに！それでは行ってきます！
so please look forward to it! Well then, I'll be right back!
足らないものなんだ 僕らの人生
What is missing? Our lives
正解どこなんだ 探せよ探せ
Where is the correct answer? Search for it, search for it
ああ足りないもの なんだろ？
Ah, what is missing?
僕らの人生
Our lives
正解どこなんだ 探せよ探せ
Where is the correct answer? Search for it, search for it
ああ例外ない 二進も三進も
Ah, no exceptions, every way is blocked
零下以内なら 劣化以外ない
If it's below zero, there's only deterioration
ああ正味クソゲーだ カラ回り回れ
Ah, it's honestly a shitty game, spinning around
ああ倦怠モード「苦」だ
Ah, it's exhausting mode, "suffering"
僕らの人生
Our lives
校内猛毒だ 屈めよ屈め
It's an internal poison, bow down, bow down
ああ盛大KNIGHT 和気あいあいゴッコは
Ah, a grand knight, playing nice together is
成敗 DIE by 生産性ない
Punishment DIE by no productivity
ああ後悔もう「独」だ 笑えよ笑え
Ah, regret is already "poison," laugh, laugh
心のレシピは
The recipe of the heart is
かまちょ味 寂ジャンキー
Attention-seeking flavor, lonely junkie
だんだん強がって
Gradually acting tough
ドロドロに付す
Getting messy and muddy
ドクドク飲み込んで
Swallowing with a gulp
苦しんで泣いて吐き出せないの
Suffering, crying, can't vomit it out,
ベノ・ベノム
venom-venom
さよなら
goodbye
ああらま 求愛性孤独毒流るる
Arama, yearning for love, loneliness, poison flowing
(愛をもっと)ちょうだいな。ねえ痛いのとんでけ
(Give me more love) Please. Hey, let the pain, pain go away
存在感血毒毒こぼるる
Existence, blood, flowing, overflowing
(ないの？もっと)
(Isn't there? More)
愛(愛)愛！(愛！)
Love (love) love! (love!)
叫べベ・ベノム、め！
Shout out venom, me!
最高点ゼロだ
It's the highest point, zero,
僕らの人生
our lives
断zenテンションローだ 屈めよ屈め
Decisively low tension, bow down, bow down
ロンリーナイト てっぺん回って
Lonely night, turning around
脳内hopeもう一度
No hesitation in the brain, hope one more time
オーバードーズけいだ 上げろ上げろ
It's an overdrive, rise up, rise up
心のなかみは
The contents of the heart are
無理オブ無理ジャンキー
impossible, impossible junkie
だんだん強がって
Getting stronger and stronger,
バラバラに付す
falling apart
ドクドク飲み込んで
Swallowing with a gulp,
苦しんで泣いて逃げ出せないの
suffering, crying, can't escape,
ベノ・ベノム
venom-venom
ああらま 求愛性孤独毒流るる
Arama, yearning for love, loneliness, poison flowing
(愛をもっと)ちょうだいな。ねえ痛いのとんでけ
(Give me more love) Please. Hey, let the pain, pain go away
存在感気毒毒欲しがるる
Existence, poison, desiring
(ないの？もっと)
(Isn't there? More)
愛(愛)愛！(愛！)
Love (love) love! (love!)
滅べベ・ベノム、め！
Perish, venom, me!
もう悪性届く毒回るる
Already corrupted, reaching, poison flowing
(愛でもっと)生涯な
(With more love) Lifetime
ねえ痛い痛いのシクシク
Hey, it hurts, it hurts, sobbing
存在抹消毒毒消えるるる
Existence, destruction, poison, disappearing
(ないの？ずっと。)
(Isn't there? Forever)
愛！愛！愛！愛！
Love! Love! Love! Love!
求愛性孤独毒流るる
Yearning for love, loneliness, poison flowing
(愛をもっと)ちょうだいな。ねえ痛いのとんでけ
(Give me more love) Please. Hey, let the pain, pain go away
存在感血毒毒こぼるる
Existence, blood, flowing, overflowing
(ないの？もっと)
(Isn't there? More)
愛(愛)愛！(愛！)
Love (love) love! (love!)
叫べベ・ベノム
Shout out venom
叫べベ・ベノム！(め！)
Shout out venom! (me!)
求愛性孤独毒流るる
Yearning for love, loneliness, poison flowing
(愛をもっと)ちょうだいな。ねえ痛いのとんでけ
(Give me more love) Please. Hey, let the pain, pain go away
存在感血毒毒こぼるる
Existence, blood, flowing, overflowing
(ないの？もっと)
(Isn't there? More)
愛(愛)愛！(愛！)
Love (love) love! (love!)
叫べベ・ベノム、め！
Shout out venom, me!
はいということで、皆様……
So, everyone...
皆様いかがだったでしょうか？
How was it?
ちょっとね今回はちょっとかっこいいめのベノムって曲を歌わせていただきました。
For this time, I sang a cool version of "Venom."
ライブありがとう！
Thanks for the live!
ということでねここでちょこ一つ告知があります。
And with that, Choco has one announcement.
上さんお願いします！
Producer-san, please!
なんと癒月ちょこ約半年ぶりに記念ボイス出します！
Yuduki Choco is releasing a voice pack in half a year!
まあこれはね癒月ちょこが全部台本を考えて録音させて作らせていただきました。
I thought of the whole script and had it recorded.
誕生記念ボイス2021ということでね今回胸とお母様描き下ろしの おっぱいマウスパッド！
The 2021 Birthday Voice features an oppai mousepad!
なんと描き下ろしのポストカードプラス特定耳なめボイスのいただきバレンタインが全部セットで付いてくるという素晴らしいボイスをお出しします！
It comes with a postcard and special ear-licking voice!
皆様お待たせいたしました！
Thank you for waiting, everyone!
あれちょこ先生今回クリスマスとかあれ2周年記念でボイス出してないなって思ったでしょ？
You might have thought I didn't release a voice pack?
なんと今回ここにまとめ出しさせていただきました！
We gathered and released all of it right here!
ということでねぜひぜひ皆様概要欄にURLが貼ってあるのでブースの方でぜひぜひ全部セットには全部特典ついてくるのですが個別だとついてこないのでぜひぜひ全部セットの方よろしくお願いします！
Check the description and get the full set on Booth!
ということでね
So with that...
みんなもう一曲だけ歌っていいちょこ？ねえねえねえ
Everyone, can I sing just one more song?
ねぇ、もう一曲だけ歌っていい？
Hey, can I sing just one more song?
最近チョコがハマってる曲歌ってもいい？
Can I sing a song Choco's been into lately?
はい、ということで、そう、全部セットの方は期間限定なっているのでね、ぜひぜひ
Yes, so, the all-in set is available for a limited time, so please, please...
販売期間に、期間に、ぜひぜひ全部セットをお求めいただけたらと思います。
during the sales period, please make sure to get the all-in set.
耳なめボイスはね全部セットにしかついてこないので、期間限定なんでよろしくお願いします！
Ear-licking voice comes only in the all-in set, so it's time-limited, please check it out!
期待してすぐに諦めて
Expect too much and give up right away,
曖昧な答えに流されては
swept away by vague answers,
自分だけ置いて行かれるような
feeling like only I am being left behind—
そんなイメージが胸をつく夜だ
such images pierce my heart tonight.
覚えてるような
As if I remember,
覚えていないような
as if I don't remember,
憧れと記憶を彷徨うよ
wandering between yearning and memories.
僕は君のために
If I was born for you,
君は僕のために
and you for me,
生まれたならちょっと嬉しいね
I'd be a little happy.
気付いたら君色に染まってるような
Before I knew it, stained in your colors,
何気ない言葉で汚して欲しい
I want you to taint me with casual words.
ずっとわからないフリを続けてきたんだ
I kept pretending not to understand all this time,
この時が来るまで
until this moment came.
もしかして君と釣り合ってないかな？
Could it be that I'm not a match for you?
そんな不安もたまに過るけれど
Such anxieties sometimes cross my mind, but
いつも困らせてばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always troubling you.
好きだよ 好きだよ 好きだよ って伝えたい
I want to tell you, "I love you, I love you, I love you!"
傷付かないように言葉を探しても
Even if I search for words not to hurt you,
空回り 気持ちに急かされて
it backfires, hurried by my feelings.
ねぇ、間違ってるような これであってるような
Hey, is this wrong, or is this right?
二人の答え ずっとよろしくね
Our answer—please continue to be with me.
気付いたら君色に染まってるような
Before I knew it, stained in your colors,
何気ない言葉で汚して欲しい
I want you to taint me with casual words.
ずっとわからないフリを続けてきたんだ
I kept pretending not to understand all this time,
この時が来るまで
until this moment came.
もしかして君と釣り合ってないかな？
Could it be that I'm not a match for you?
そんな不安もたまに過るけれど
Such anxieties sometimes cross my mind, but
いつも困らせてばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always troubling you.
好きだよ 好きだよ 好きだよ って伝えたい
I want to tell you, "I love you, I love you, I love you!"
気付いたら君色に染まってるような
Before I knew it, stained in your colors,
何気ない言葉で汚して欲しい
I want you to taint me with casual words.
ずっとわからないフリを続けてきたんだ
I kept pretending not to understand all this time,
この時が来るまで
until this moment came.
もしかして君と釣り合ってないかな？
Could it be that I'm not a match for you?
そんな不安もたまに過るけれど
Such anxieties sometimes cross my mind, but
いつも困らせてばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always troubling you.
好きだよ 好きだよ 好きだよ って伝えたい
I want to tell you, "I love you, I love you, I love you!"
はぁ、メルさん歌ってみた、このあとプレミアム公開なので、よろしくお願いします！またねー！
Phew, that was Mel-san's "Utattemita." There's a premiere right after this, so please check it out! See you!